Curriculum Vitae

Personal details

Name Taehyun Nam
Mobile +821077304236
Email nth0419@kaist.ac.kr

Birth of date 2001.04.19.

Military Service No

Address 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Personal Statement

I'm diligent and hard-working student who wants to be part of the research that pioneering next-generation semiconductor. Now studying in KAIST.(Major: Chemical engineering) Current research interest is chemical approach to the OTFT based next-generation memory device such as RRAM, multi-logic device, etc. by using iCVD.

Relevant skills and experiences

Various software tools

- Python Data analysis & ML(Tensorflow, scikit-learn), Pro/ii, Aspen, C, Matlab
- Various experience of software tools in the fields of Chemical engineering
- General computer skills: MS Office, Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender, Premier Pro, After effect, etc.

Research experiences

- Intern in the Lotte Chemical R&D center(Daejeon), Intellectual Property
 Management Department, worked on all-solid-state battery IP(2022.7~2022.8)
- Research student in KAIST Chemical and biological Engineering department functional thin film lab, studied OTFT research by using iCVD(2022.1~2022.2)
- Research student in POSTECH Chemical Eng. energy material lab, studied metal oxide nano-structure anode battery(2021.9~2021.12)
- Intern in the SKHynix Institute of Future technology, Advanced 3D NAND development team, Metal connection(M0) related works(2021.6~2021.8)

External activities

- POSTECH department of Chemical engineering representative(2020.9~2021.2)
- Photography club ("빛노을") vice president(2020.3~2021.8)
- POSTECH library council (LAON) design team leader(2020.3~2021.8)
- Various mentoring experiences(Samsung Engineering environment school mentor, POSTECH winter engineering camp, etc.)

GPA and Language skills

Undergraduate GPA: 4.06/4.3(2022.12.), Percentage equivalent: 98/100, Rank: 1/27

• Relevant coursework: Physical chemistry, Thermodynamics, Organic Chem. lab TOEIC score: 975/990, RC 480 / LC 495 (Test date: 2021.02.21.)



TOEFL score: 100/120, 30/26/24/20(R/L/S/W) (Test date: 2019.08.10.) JLPT(Japanese Language Proficient Test) score: JLPT N1, 129/180 (Test date: 2022.12.04.)

Education History

Feb 2023 - Current M.S. student in chemical and biomolecular engineering at KAIST

Feb 2019 - Feb 2023 B.S. degree in chemical engineering at POSTECH

Mar 2017 - Feb 2019 Daejeon Dongshin Science Highschool (early graduation)

Awards

Feb 2021 - Feb 2023 National Science & Technology Scholarship, Korea Student Aid foundation (full tuition, merit-based scholarship)

Feb 2019 - Dec 2020 Jigok scholarship, POSTECH (full tuition for 4 semester)

Publications (SCIE & ESCI)

Publications (Domestic)

Conferences

Patents